{
    "id": "a075894b3ec54b40980945393ce215e8",
    "title": "For, To, and So That | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "af21d97450584c76aaeada0a2c47a2b5",
            "title": "For, To and So That",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I talked to the shy girl ............................ she wouldn't feel left out.",
                    "description": "We use 'so' to indicate the result or effect.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "to",
                        "so"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We stopped at the pub .............................. a drink.",
                    "description": "Only the infinitive can be used to express a person's purpose.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to have",
                        "for having",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We stopped at the pub ........................ a drink.",
                    "description": "'For' can indicate purpose when it is followed by a noun. It cannot be used before a verb to express purpose. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "for having",
                        "to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I went to Canada ............................ my brother.",
                    "description": "Only the infinitive can be used to express a person's purpose. 'For' can indicate it only when it is followed by a noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to see",
                        "for seeing",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "What do I need to get ............................... dinner?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "to",
                        "for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Sort your rubbish .............................. recycling.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "to",
                        "for",
                        "so"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I took the phone back to the store ....................... a replacement.",
                    "description": "Only the infinitive can be used to express a person's purpose. 'For' can indicate it only when it is followed by a noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to get",
                        "for getting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We started early ........................... we wouldn't be late.",
                    "description": "In an informal style that can be dropped after so.",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "so that",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You need to be over 18 ......................... that film.",
                    "description": "Only the infinitive can be used to express a person's purpose. 'For' can indicate it only when it is followed by a noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for watching",
                        "to watch",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am leaving early today ........................... the rush hour traffic.",
                    "description": "Only the infinitive can be used to express a person's purpose. 'For' can indicate it only when it is followed by a noun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for avoiding",
                        "to avoid",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am putting the meat in the oven now, .......................... it will be ready by eight o'clock.",
                    "description": "We use 'so that' before a clause to indicate purpose.",
                    "answers": [
                        "so that",
                        "for",
                        "that"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am angry with you ........................... me up.",
                    "description": "For can be followed by an ing form after a description of a reaction to explain the behavior that caused it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to wake",
                        "for waking",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}